ANDREW THIESEN

Technical Account Manager | Senior Engineer andrew@thiesen.co | 954-683-5060 | 5770 Copper Leaf Lane, Naples, FL 34116

SUMMARY

Experienced Technical Account Manager/Senior Engineer with expertise in cloud products, SAAS services, software, hardware, networking, and security. Strong communication, customer service, project management, relationship-building, analytical, problem-solving, and sales skills. Capable of simplifying complex technical concepts, meeting client needs promptly and professionally, managing timelines, building client relationships, analyzing data for trends, resolving issues efficiently, and identifying growth opportunities.

SKILLS

API Design | AWS | Azure | Bug Tracking | Budgeting | ChatGPT | CI & CD | Client Relationship Building | Confluence | Defect Analysis and Resolution | Excel | Forecasting | GCP | Git | Github | Go | HTML | ISO | JIRA | Mac OS | MS 365 | Node.js | Office 365 | OpenAI | Powerpoint | Python | S3 | Software Documentation Control | Software Testing and Validation | SOC-2 | SQL | SSMS | VCS | Web3 | Windows OS | Word | WSDL

EXPERIENCE

Freespace - Application Support Engineer, Naples, FL: 08/2022 - 11/2022

- Collaborated with developers, analysts, and project managers to quickly resolve incidents.
- Conducted software application and disaster recovery testing to ensure business readiness after fail-overs.
- Provided support for web- and client-based applications, file and data feeds, and batch processes to minimize impact on business.
- Analyzed and mapped data, and wrote SQL scripts to extract data from SQL databases.

Sensory Inc - Solutions Architect, Boulder, CO: 10/2021 - 08/2022

- Worked with developers and engineers to implement technological solutions.
- Maintained an in-depth understanding of business processes, needs, and objectives.
- Translated technical ideas and issues into non-technical terms for business executives.
- Contributed significantly to the product development lifecycle of both back-end and customer-facing solutions.
- Authored development guidelines to accelerate application design efforts through prebuilt frameworks.

Exterro - Senior Implementation Engineer, Beaverton, OR: 07/2017 - 10/2021

- Conducted various tests on processes and created documents.
- Worked with technical staff to conduct system audits and execute implementations on time and within functional parameters.
- Configured and implemented system software changes.
- Assisted clients in monitoring all software implementation lifecycles.
- Maintained existing applications and designed and delivered new applications.
- Managed accounts exceeding 1 Million USD ARR.
- Developed and executed solutions to customer needs and drivers through hands-on engagement.
- Established long-term, trusted partner relationships to manage stakeholder expectations and achieve revenue growth goals.
- Identified and proposed upsell and renewal opportunities, and communicated value proposition to reduce churn results for enterprise customers.
- Participated in product innovation by identifying and representing customer needs and presenting new product capabilities.
- Provided technical troubleshooting and problem-solving for clients with installed equipment or system issues.

Hyperion Insurance Group (Contract) - Service Desk Analyst, Naples, FL: 07/2017 - 10/2021

- Provided user support via phone, email, and chat channels.
- Entered service tickets into an incident tracking system for faster problem resolution.
- Resolved user issues with desktop computers, laptops, and mobile devices.
- Identified and addressed hardware, network infrastructure, and connectivity issues that prevented users from completing tasks.
- Diagnosed and fixed system functionality issues to enable desired operations.

Naples Grande Beach Resort (Contract) - IT Manager, Naples, FL: 07/2016 - 10/2016

- Reviewed and evaluated project requirements and costs related to architecture design, implementation, testing, and deployment needs.
- Established and implemented an enterprise security strategy for network and hardware, disaster recovery, data protection, and endpoint protection.
- Conducted software license audits to mitigate compliance risk and reduce costs.
- Recommended innovative and automated solutions for routine tasks.
- Created storage allocation for new and existing Windows servers and clusters.

Naples Grande Beach Resort (Contract) - IT Manager, Naples, FL: 07/2016 - 10/2016

- Managed network and system performance by conducting troubleshooting, security patching, and maintenance.
- Oversaw IT department operations and provided training.
- Collaborated closely with project members to identify and address problems.
- Supported physical equipment such as phones, copiers, and fax machines.
- Guided technology strategy and roadmaps for the organization.

Liquid Holdings Group - Manager Technical Process and Maintenance, Aventura, FL: 01/2012 - 01/2015

- Suggested technical process improvements to optimize resources.
- Evaluated customer, reputation, and regulatory risks.
- Communicated with technology leaders across multiple teams on project execution.
- Designed, implemented, and monitored application integration while coordinating updates and developing test cases.
- Recruited and trained IT team members.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, St. Petersburg College, St. Petersburg, FL Bachelor of Science Information Technology, UAT, Tempe, AXZ

AA History, Truckee Meadows Community College, Reno, NV High School Diploma, Washoe High School, Reno, NV

ADDITIONAL SKILLS, MEMBERSHIPS, CERTIFICATIONS, MEDIA

ASL - Beginner

Polish Language - Advanced ISSA Member

Github: https://github.com/thiesaj

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ajthiesen

Credly: https://www.credly.com/users/thiesaj/badges